Guide to the Amos Vogel Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Photographs, 1920-1999
  - Subseries IV.2: Film Stills, 1920-1994
    - Historia Naturae, 1967 (Box 138, Folder 15)
    - Hitler, A Film From Germany, 1978 (Box 138, Folder 16)
    - Home Sweet Home, 1969 (Box 138, Folder 17)
    - Homoparadoksum, 1989-1990 (Box 138, Folder 18)
    - Inauguration of the Pleasure Dome, 1954 (Box 138, Folder 19)
    - Indigenous Women, 1982 (Box 138, Folder 20)
    - Isydi!, 1991 (Box 138, Folder 21)
    - Jacoba, 1987 (Box 138, Folder 22)
    - Je T'aime, je t'aime, 1968 (Box 138, Folder 23)
    - Jean Jacques, undated (Box 138, Folder 24)
    - Jiddische Kultur im jüdischen Staat, 1992 (Box 138, Folder 25)
    - Jidl mint fidl, 1936 (Box 138, Folder 26)
    - Joe and Maxi, 1980 (Box 138, Folder 27)
    - Kaya, I'll Kill You, 1967 (Box 138, Folder 28)
    - Kchsiner, 1988 (Box 138, Folder 29)
    - King Kong, 1933 (Box 138, Folder 30)
    - Klinkaart, 1950s (Box 138, Folder 31)
    - The Knave of Hearts, 1954 (Box 138, Folder 32)
    - Krotki Film o Milosci, 1988 (Box 138, Folder 33)
    - Kto Stutschitsjav Dwerj Ko Mne?, 1982 (Box 138, Folder 34)
    - Kwaidan, 1966 (Box 138, Folder 35)
    - La Boca del Lobo, 1988 (Box 138, Folder 36)
    - Lady of the Tracks, 1966 (Box 138, Folder 37)
    - Landschaft im Nebel, undated (Box 139, Folder 1)
    - La Vie de Bohème, 1992 (Box 139, Folder 2)
    - Linda/Les and Annie, 1991 (Box 139, Folder 3)
    - Lingo, 1979 (Box 139, Folder 4)
    - Living, 1971 (Box 139, Folder 5)
    - Living in Oblivion, undated (Box 139, Folder 6)
    - The Lion Has Seven Heads, 1971 (Box 139, Folder 7)
    - Lodz Ghetto, 1988 (Box 139, Folder 8)
    - Lucia, 1969 (Box 139, Folder 9)
    - Lysis, 1948 (Box 139, Folder 10)
    - Mahanagar, 1963 (Box 139, Folder 11)
    - Malenkaja Vera, 1988 (Box 139, Folder 12)
    - Man with a Movie Camera, 1929 (Box 139, Folder 13)
    - Menil Mon Tant, 1925 (Box 139, Folder 14)
    - Menschen wie aus Glas, 1982 (Box 139, Folder 15)
    - Meshes of the Afternoon, 1943 (Box 139, Folder 16)
    - The Midnight Parasites, 1960s (Box 139, Folder 17)
    - The Miraculous Maiden (Virgin), 1966 (Box 139, Folder 18)
    - The Mirage, 1959 (Box 139, Folder 19)
    - Mistress of the Rings, 1992 (Box 139, Folder 20)
    - Mit starrem Blick aufs Geld, 1983 (Box 139, Folder 21)
    - The Moon Is Blue, 1953 (Box 139, Folder 22)
    - More Light, undated (Box 139, Folder 23)
    - Morels Invention, undated (Box 139, Folder 24)
    - Motorway, undated (Box 139, Folder 25)
    - Music Studio, 1950s (Box 139, Folder 26)
    - Nagunenun Gilesodo Schizi Annunda, 1987 (Box 139, Folder 27)
    - Neurasia, 1968 (Box 139, Folder 28)
    - Night Sun, 1990 (Box 139, Folder 29)
    - Object Lesson, 1950 (Box 139, Folder 30)
    - Odinokij Golos Tschelowjeka, 1987 (Box 139, Folder 31)
    - Of the Dead, 1979 (Box 139, Folder 32)
    - Oramunde, 1933 (Box 139, Folder 33)
    - Parallel Space, 1992 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - The Parson's Widow, 1920 (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - Passenger, 1961-1963 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - Pat's Birthday, 1962 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - Pelle the Conqueror, 1988 (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - Penthesilea, 1983 (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - Picnic, undated (Box 140, Folder 7)
    - Polish Abstract Films, undated (Box 140, Folder 8)
    - Portraits of Women, 1970 (Box 140, Folder 9)
    - Puce Moment, 1949 (Box 140, Folder 10)
    - Pull My Daisy, 1959 (Box 140, Folder 11)
    - Psyche, 1949 (Box 140, Folder 12)
    - Razor Blades, undated (Box 140, Folder 13)
    - Recruits in Ingolstadt, 1971 (Box 140, Folder 14)
    - Reed, México Insurgente, 1973 (Box 140, Folder 15)
    - Reflections, undated (Box 140, Folder 16)
    - Regisseur Krzysztof Kieslowski, 1988 (Box 140, Folder 17)
    - Reisen in Landesinnere, 1988 (Box 140, Folder 18)
    - Related By Choice, 1968 (Box 140, Folder 19)
    - The Return of the Secaucus Seven, 1980 (Box 140, Folder 20)
    - The Rite, 1969 (Box 140, Folder 21)
    - Robison No Niwa, 1986-1987 (Box 140, Folder 22)
    - La Ronde, 1950 (Box 140, Folder 23)
    - Ruby, 1970 (Box 140, Folder 24)
    - Salaam Bombay I, 1988 (Box 140, Folder 25)
    - Salomé, 1971 (Box 140, Folder 26)
    - Salvador, 1985 (Box 140, Folder 27)
    - Sashshennyj fonarj Die angezündete Laterne, 1983 (Box 140, Folder 28)
    - Satyricon, 1969 (Box 140, Folder 29)
    - Shadow of Doubt, undated (Box 140, Folder 30)
    - Shooting Script, 1992 (Box 140, Folder 31)
    - Shu Jian En Chou Lou, 1987 (Box 140, Folder 32)
    - Siberia, undated (Box 140, Folder 33)
    - Silent Scream, 1985 (Box 140, Folder 34)
    - 69, 1969 (Box 140, Folder 35)
    - Skinless Night, 1991 (Box 140, Folder 36)
    - Sonambients: Sound Sculpture of Harry Bertoia, undated (Box 140, Folder 37)
    - Sonezaki Shinju, 1982 (Box 140, Folder 38)
    - The Spiders Strategem, 1969-1970 (Box 140, Folder 39)
    - La Strada, 1954 (Box 140, Folder 40)
    - The Stunt Man, 1980 (Box 140, Folder 41)
    - Subject Lesson, 1956 (Box 140, Folder 42)
    - Survivors, undated (Box 140, Folder 43)
    - Sweet Movie, 1974 (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - Swoon, 1992 (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - Symphonie, 1980 (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - Taiga, 1992-1992 (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - Talking to the Enemy, undated (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - Terry Whitmore, for Example, 1969 (Box 141, Folder 6)
    - Testament, 1988 (Box 141, Folder 7)
    - The Bed, 1968 (Box 141, Folder 8)
    - The Child, undated (Box 141, Folder 9)
    - The Draughtman's Contract, 1982 (Box 141, Folder 10)
    - The Future of Video, 1986-1987 (Box 141, Folder 11)
    - The Holy Fool, undated (Box 141, Folder 12)
    - The Houses Are Full of Smoke, 1987 (Box 141, Folder 13)
    - The Living Paintings, undated (Box 141, Folder 14)
    - The Lost Generation, 1982 (Box 141, Folder 15)
    - The Madman at the Crossroads, undated (Box 141, Folder 16)
    - The Man Without a World, 1991 (Box 141, Folder 17)
    - The Red and the White, 1967 (Box 141, Folder 18)
    - The Round Up, 1966 (Box 141, Folder 19)
    - The Street of Crocodiles, 1986 (Box 141, Folder 20)
    - The Transfigured Body, 1991 (Box 141, Folder 21)
    - The Will to Provoke, 1988 (Box 141, Folder 22)
    - Thigh Like Lyre Triangular, 1961 (Box 141, Folder 23)
    - Through the Garden, undated (Box 141, Folder 24)
    - Tout Va Bien, 1972 (Box 141, Folder 25)
    - Tshal, 1994 (Box 141, Folder 26)
    - Tup-Tup, 1972 (Box 141, Folder 27)
    - Un Chien Delicieux, 1991 (Box 141, Folder 28)
    - Unreconciled, 1965 (Box 141, Folder 29)
    - Unser Berlin hat keinen Vorname, 1992 (Box 141, Folder 30)
    - Vampyr, 1972 (Box 141, Folder 31)
    - Vermischte Nachrichten, 1986 (Box 141, Folder 32)
    - Vienna Is Different 50 Years After the Anschluss, 1988 (Box 141, Folder 33)
    - Voices from the Attic, 1988 (Box 141, Folder 34)
    - Wave, 1948 (Box 141, Folder 35)
    - Weekend, 1967 (Box 141, Folder 36)
    - We Were so Beloved, 1986 (Box 141, Folder 37)
    - When the Tomcat Comes, 1963 (Box 141, Folder 38)
    - Why Did You Wake Me with a Kiss, 1967 (Box 141, Folder 39)
    - World Apartment Horror, 1991 (Box 141, Folder 40)
    - Zawrocony, 1994 (Box 141, Folder 41)
    - Zerreissprobe, undated (Box 141, Folder 42)
    - Negatives, undated, 1981 (Box 141, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous
      - General, undated, 1980s (Box 141, Folder 44)
      - Berlin Film Festival, 1983 (Box 141, Folder 45)
      - Berlin Film Festival, 1988 (Box 141, Folder 46)
  - Subseries IV.3: Slides, 1970s-1988
    Subseries 3 consists of slides from Vogel's courses taught at the Annenberg School of Communication, University of Pennsylvania. These are the visual guides to the extensive lecture notes held in Series III, Subseries 4. The majority of the slides indicate what course they relate to as well as the lecture title.
    - "American Artists," 1982 (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - Class 4: "Dada and Pop Art," 1980s (Box 142, Folder 2)
    - Communications 320
      - "Worldview," 1988 (Box 142, Folder 3)
      - "Ford II," 1978-1983 (Box 142, Folder 4)
      - Class 2, undated (Box 142, Folder 5)
      - "World View of Modern Filmmakers I," 1980s (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - Communication 520, 1970s-1980s (Box 142, Folder 7)
    - Discards, undated, 1980-1981 (Box 142, Folder 8)
    - "Expressionism," 1970s-1980s (Box 142, Folder 9)
    - "Graffiti," 1985 (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Magnifications, 1982 (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - "A Primer of Visual Literacy," undated (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1980s (Box 143, Folder 4)
- Series V: Audio Visual Material, 1946-1980s
  Series V contains audio visual material the bulk of which is audiocassette tapes. Recorded onto the tapes are interviews of Amos Vogel, film conferences and special events, soundtracks to various independent films, and lecture notes. Of interest are several interviews conducted by Vogel with such notable individuals as Werner Herzog, Yoko Ono, Bernardo Bertolucci, and Ingmar Bergman. There is also a small amount of original soundtracks on 33 ½ LPs.
  - Audiocassettes (Box Index 2)
    - Angelopoulos, Theodores--Days of 36, 1973
    - A Movie--Visuals and Sound, undated
    - Before the Revolution, 1964 (3 tapes)
    - Bergman, Ingmar, 1973
    - Bertolucci, Bernardo, 1970 September
    - "Computer Film as Art," 1974 January (3 tapes)
    - Conrad, Tony--Outside the Dream Syndicate, 1972
    - Critics Forum I, 1972 December 10 (2 tapes)
    - Critics Forum II, 1973 February 19
    - Dear Friends Soundtrack, 1980s
    - Discussion of M'Claines Film, undated
    - F for Fake with Commentary, 1970s (2 tapes) (Box Index 3)
    - Fata Morgana, 1971 May 17
    - Foucault, Michel and Sennet, Richard, 1980 November 20
    - "Freetime" with Jonas Mekas, Amos Vogel et al., 1971 May 3
    - Going Places, Inside Cracle Corners, Make Mine Freedom, Meet King Joe, Notorious Excerpts, 1946-1951, 1974
    - "Harlem, Voices, Faces," 1974
    - Hearts and Minds Soundtrack, 1974
    - Herzog, Werner, 1970 September
    - Herzog, Werner, 1971
    - Janscó, Miklós, 1970 April (3 tapes)
    - Kleist--General, 1977 October 15 (2 tapes)
    - Kleist--The Marquise of O, 1976 December (2 tapes)
    - Life of an American Fireman Soundtrack, 1974 (2 tapes) (Box Index 4)
    - Lingo (Dormant Human Brain), 1979
    - Losey, Joseph Pres Conference, 1971
    - Makavejev, Dušan
      - Interview with Amos Vogel at Cannes, 1971
      - Mysteries of the Organism Press Conference, 1971 May 21
      - Sweet Movie, 1974 October (3 tapes)
      - Sweet Movie soundtrack, 1974 (2 tapes)
    - MOMA Television Conference, 1974 January (5 tapes)
    - MOMA Television Conference, 1974 January (Box Index 5)
    - Ono, Yoko, 1970 May 21
    - Robbe-Grillet, 1972 April 24 (2 tapes)Schaeffer, Pierre, 1972 April 28
    - Schmid, Daniel, 1974 October (2 tapes)
    - Triumph of Will, 1977
    - Umberto D., 1975 September
    - Vogel, Amos
      - Boston, 1972 (Box Index 5)
      - Collier Show--Film as a Subversive Art, 1975 February
      - Collier Show--Obscenity, 1974 March
      - Cunningham, Shawn, 1986 May 22
      - Deren, Maya, 1977
      - EFLA, 1971
      - Gross, Terry, 1980 (Box Index 6)
      - New York Film Council Symposium, 1974 March 23
      - Television Series Rehearsal, 1980
      - Vogel, Amos and Stephen discuss the Shining, 1980 June
      - WKHY-FM to discuss Film as a Subversive Art, 1975
    - WR--Mysteries With Commentary, 1976 June 1
    - Young Mr. Lincoln
      - Class Analysis, 1976 November (2 tapes)
      - Commentary, undated (2 tapes)
      - Dialogue, undated (2 tapes)
    - Yoshida--Coup D'Etat at Cannes, 1973
  - Records (Box Index 7)
    - Before the Revolution, 1969
    - Eros + Massacre, 1969
    - Viva la Muerte, 1971 (2 records)
- Series VI: Personal, 1932-2000
  This small series contains personal material of Amos Vogel's and information about him as an individual, not necessarily about his professional work. The series has been arranged in two subseries: Early Life and About Amos Vogel.
  - Subseries VI.1: About Amos Vogel, 1960s-2000
    Subseries 1 is comprised of records about Amos Vogel and is arranged topically. The bulk of the material is from the documentary produced by Egon Humer about the expulsion of Jewish individuals from Austria. Included with this material is correspondence, publicity-related documents, and printed material. Other documents consist of interviews with Amos Vogel, reviews and articles about his written works, reference letters submitted as evidence that he should receive tenure at the University of Pennsylvania, and awards that were given to him.
    - Anthology Film Archives Award, 1994 February 22 (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Articles about Amos Vogel, 1961, 1992-1996 (Box 144, Folder 2)
    - Honorary Membership in Society for Cinema Studies, 1992 (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Humer Film
      - Correspondence
        - 1993-1994 (Box 144, Folder 4)
        - 1995 January-June (Box 144, Folder 5)
        - 1995 September-1996 February (Box 144, Folder 6)
        - 1996 March-2000 February (Box 144, Folder 7)
      - Form Letters, 1994 (Box 145, Folder 1)
      - Notes by Vogel for Humer, 1990-1994 (Box 145, Folder 2)
      - Pending Candidates, 1994 (Box 145, Folder 3)
      - Publicity, 1995-1996, (2 Folders) (Box 145, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Questionnaires, 1994, (2 Folders) (Box 145, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Interviews
      - Fire Island News, 1989 Summer (Box 145, Folder 8)
      - Macdonald, Scott, 1984-1985 (Box 145, Folder 9)
      - The New York Post, 1965 (Box 145, Folder 10)
      - The New York Times, 1968 (Box 145, Folder 11)
      - Nichols, Mike, 1983 (Box 146, Folder 1)
      - Pennsylvania Gazette, 1973 (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - Literarischen Colloquium in Berlin, 1989 December (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - Personal Letters, 1972, 1993-1995 (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Reference Letters, 1976 (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - Response to Annenberg School Questionnaire, 1987 May (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - Reviews
      - Le Monde, 1978 February 22 (Box 146, Folder 7)
      - Little Loring Book, 1963 Fall (Box 146, Folder 8)
      - Russian Essay and Critique, 1985 (Box 146, Folder 9)
    - "A Sampling of Czechoslovakian Television," 1968 (Box 146, Folder 10)
    - Support Letters Concerning IRS Case, 1991 (Box 146, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1960s-2000 (Box 146, Folder 12)
  - Subseries VI.2: Early Life, 1932-1937
    Subseries 2 holds documents dating from Vogel's childhood. A Tagebuch entitled "Zwischen 15 und 17" and a journal from his art class in 1932 are found here. Both of these items are in German.
    - Cizek Zeitschrift, 1932 September (Box 146, Folder 13)
    - "Zwischen 15 und 17" Ein Tagebuch, 1937 (Box 146, Folder 14)
    - Juvenalia-- Drawings and Schoolwork (Box 148)
    - Juvenalia-- Drawings and Schoolwork (Box 149)
    - Family Documents--Matel Vogelbaum Immigration Documents (Box 149)
    - Scrapbook (Box 149)